Hi, so I just won't talk to you
about the UI changes that you may see
between my videos and AWS.
So just to explain things to you,
AWS is doing a huge transition of their interface
to a new guidelines for design.
And so in that regards, sometimes the UI will look new
and this is what I call a new type of UI
and it looks like pretty square and so on,
but sometimes you will have the old kind of UIs,
which looks like this.
And so AWS is doing a transition for all their services,
of all their UIs and it's not all at the same time.
It happens over one year or two years
and it's still happening today.
So my goal is obviously to have videos
as updated as possible, but it is literally impossible
to keep up with all the changes
until they're done with them.
So what I'm doing is that I try my best to keep my videos
up to date if they are breaking changes,
but if I believe that the changes are minor enough
that you can find your way around the console,
I will not update the video just yet, but trust me,
I do listen to feedback
and whenever a video is outdated,
I will go ahead and update it.
Okay.
Another thing you can do is that if you really are lost,
you can switch a toggle in most of the services
that have a new experience and switch back to the old UI.
If you do switch back to the old UI like here
as you can see, you will see the old UI sometimes
like you see in my videos, but really I just wanted
to give you a little warning just to explain to you
the course is not outdated.
It is my passion and my duty to make sure
that you pass your exam and learn a lot in this course
and so trust me, I am monitoring every single day
for updates and changes that are breaking my course
and if they do break my course,
I promise that I will update my videos, but please, please,
please forgive me in advance
if the video doesn't look as updated as the UI in AWS,
it is very difficult right now
to keep up with their changes.
So thank you so much and I wish you a very happy learning.