Now, one last touch before get started
with this course.
I will be referring to
the Shared Responsibility Model quite a lot.
And you will see this diagram at the end of this course.
This is what define what is your responsibility
versus AWS when using the cloud
and there is a shared responsibility.
You as a customer, you're responsible
for the security in the cloud.
So whatever you use in the cloud,
however you configure it is your entire responsibility.
That includes security, your data, your operating system,
your network and firewall configuration, et cetera.
And AWS is going to be responsible
for the security of the cloud.
So all the infrastructure, all the hardware,
all the software, all their own internal security,
they are responsible of.
And this is why we have shared responsibility.
In the Certified Cloud Practitioner exam,
you will be asked some questions around finding
what is your responsibility
and what is the responsibility of AWS.
So I just wanted to give you a quick overview of this
and in some sections I will be referring back
to this diagram and this model to tell you
what is your responsibility
and what is the responsibility of AWS.
Finally, when you use AWS,
you are agreeing to their Acceptable Use Policy,
which you can find right here
and I think it's pretty obvious
that you cannot do any illegal,
harmful of offensive use or content,
you cannot do any security violation,
you cannot abuse a network
and you cannot do email or other types of messages abuse.
All of that makes sense but it's good to specify it.
Now , I hope you're excited.
We're gonna get started with this course
and actually get to use the cloud.
So, I will see you in the next section.